JAKE BAEK

WEB DEVELOPER TORONTO, ON

	jakejonggubaek@gmail.com
in	<u>/jakejonggubaek</u>
#	<u>/jakejonggubaek</u>
	Portfolio: jakeisbaek.me

PERSONAL PROFILE

As an experienced web developer I understand the importance of writing accessible and responsive design with DRY and clean code. My passion for problem solving, an eagerness to learn and adapt to new technologies are strengthened by my on-going & previous experiences in web development & consulting roles.

SKILLS

Front End Skills







JavaScript



CSS3

React

Jest









Responsive

Component

graphQL



NoSOL

And More

Npm, Git, Heroku, LESS, MongoDB, Firebase, REST API, Google Analytics, Customer service. Team-based development

CERTIFICATE

- Google Analytics
- Codecademy: Node.js, Vue.js, jQuery

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Juno College, Mentor

APR 2021 - FEB 2022

 Assisted cohort 32, 33, Coding 101 Workshop

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Soulfx technologies, React Developer JUN 2021 - PRESENT

- Website development for Centennial College with React, TypeScript, and Styled Component. (https://www.centennialcollege.ca)
- Web application development for pharmaceutical companies with React, TypeScript, Styled Component, graphQL, and Jest

Samsung SDS, Junior Web Developer JAN 2013 - JUL 2015

- Managed main page, sign in, log in/out systems (https://samsungfire.com/m) using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, SQL, SVN in a cross functional team.
- Improved client's (Samsung F&M Insurance) web application without major issue, maintained the system by proactively monitoring live logs to ensure quality with responsibility, and enhanced accessibility & launched a new mobile application

EDUCATION

Juno College, JavaScript / Immersive Bootcamp AUG 2020 - MAR 2021

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript / ES6, React, REST APIs, Firebase, Git
- Responsive UI, accessibility(WCAG), Paired programming

Hanyang Univ., Urban Engineering FEB 2007 - FEB 2013

 GPA(4.01/4.5), Statistical Programming(SAS), Data Analysis, Adobe Photoshop, Mathematics, Physics, GIS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Popsipoll, <link>

HTML, CSS, SASS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, FIREBASE

 A responsive React project that provides create / share / vote polls & poll results with dark / light mode and preview poll functions.

Random Recipe, <link>

HTML, CSS, SASS, JAVASCRIPT, RESTFUL API, PAIRED PROGRAMMING

• A responsive web application that provides random recipe based on what users have in their fridge.

Team To-Do-List, <link>

HTML, SASS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, NODE.JS, MONGODB

• A full stack application that provides to-do-list and realtime chat which users can share with their teammates.